A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, General Files (Room 5600), 2001-2006, RG 55 FA1254
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Religion, 2001-2006; 14
  - Religion - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 51, Folder 1-4)
    Includes: Rev. Abraham K. Akaka Ministries Foundation; American and Foreign Christian Union; American Friends of Yeshiva L'tzeirim "Ner Israel"; American Jewish Committee; Anti-Defamation League; Arrow Leadership Ministries; Association of Professional Chaplains; Association for Religion and Intellectual Life; Balm of Gilead, Inc.; Boughton Place; Campus Crusade for Christ International; Committee of 100 for Tibet; Council on Spiritual Practices; Daily Word; Diocese of New Hampshire; Episcopal Charities; Faith Matters; Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies; Fellowship of Christians in Universities and Schools; Fellowship of the Crown; Foundation for Conscious Evolution; Global Peace Initiative of Women Religious and Spiritual Leaders; Billy Graham Evangelistic Association; Hosea Foundation; Incarnation Center; Institute on Religion and Public Life; Mount Saviour Monastery; National Bible Association; North Universalist Chapel Society; Norwegian Seamen's Church; Oak Chapel; Peaceful Dwelling Project; Peale Center for Christian Living; Pocono Mountain Ecumenical Hunger Ministry; Quebec - Labrador Foundation; Religion and Ethics; Spiritual Alliances, LLC; State Patrol Chaplain's Association; Temple of Understanding; Templeton Prize for Progress in Religion; Bob Thurman Proposals; Tibet House U.S.; UNITY; United Jewish Appeal - Federation of New York; Zen Studies Society.
  - Atrium Society, 2001-2006 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Center for Contemplative Mind in Society, 2001-2006 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Christian Ministry in the National Parks, 2001-2006 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Crestone Mountain Zen Center, 2001-2006 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Episcopal Diocese of Arkansas, 2001-2006 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Foundation for Conscious Evolution, 2001-2006 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Healthcare Chaplaincy, 2001-2006 (Box 52, Folder 4-5, Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Interfaith Alliance, 2001-2006 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Interfaith Center of New York, 2001-2006 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Spiritual Life Institute, 2001-2006 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - John Templeton Foundation, 2001-2006 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Tricycle, 2001-2006 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Upaya Zen Center, 2001-2006 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Cemetery - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    Woodstock Burying Ground Association
  - Churches - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
    Includes: All Souls Unitarian Church; Brick Presbyterian Church, New York, NY; Presbyterian Church, New York, NY; Episcopal Church in Jackson Hole; First Congregational Church, Woodstock, VT; First Presbyterian Church of New Canaan, CT; Friends of Canterbury Cathedral; Cathedral Church of St. Stephen; Central Presbyterian Church; Christ Church Center; Christ Episcopal Church; Church of the Transfiguration; Diocese of New Hampshire; Lamington Presbyterian Church (LSR anonymous gift); Orleans Church Building Foundation; St. James Episcopal Church; Saint John's Episcopal Church; St. John's Lutheran Church; Saint Luke's Episcopal Church; St. Mary's Episcopal Anglican Church; Saint Paul's Church; Union Church Fair.
  - Churches - Cathedral Church of St. John the Divine, New York, NY, 2001-2006 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Churches - Riverside Church, 2001-2006 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Churches - Union Church of Pocantico Hills, 2001-2006 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Missions - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    New York City Mission Society.
  - Missions - Quebec-Labrador Foundation (QLF), 2001-2006 (Box 54, Folder 7)
- Rockefeller Family, 2001-2006; 15
  - Rockefeller Family - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Rockefeller Family Forum, 2001-2006 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    Restricted - Open in 2029
  - Rockefeller Family Weekend, 2003 June-2004 June (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Rockefeller Family Fund, 2001-2006 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - A-B, 2001-2006 (Box 57, Folder 3-6)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - B-D, 2001-2006 (Box 59, Folder 1-9, Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Henry Diamond, 2003 (Box 60, Folder 2-3)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - E-F, 2001-2006 (Box 60, Folder 4-6)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - F-J, 2001-2006 (Box 61, Folder 1-12)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - J-M, 2001-2006 (Box 62, Folder 1-11)
    Including Lady Bird Johnson and others.
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - M-R, 2001-2006 (Box 63, Folder 1-9)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Rockefeller - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 58, Folder 3-4)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Rockefeller, Steven, 2001-2006 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - S-V, 2001-2006 (Box 64, Folder 1-10)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - W-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 65, Folder 1-5)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Autographs and Photographs - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    Includes: Gene Bonini; James F. Bretz; D. Gilham-Jones; Frederick Melhado; Nik Neville.
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Awards - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    Includes: Carnegie Award; Marquis Who's Who Publication Board.
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Awards - British Virgin Islands Belonger Ceremony, 2003 September 26 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Birthday, 2002-2004 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    Includes: 92nd, 93rd, and 94th Birthday.
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Consultants - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Estate of, 2001-2006 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Gifts - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Gifts - Foote, Suzanne, 2001-2006 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Great Letters to LSR, 2001-2004 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Philanthropy - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    Includes: Oomingmak.
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Politics - Absentee Ballot (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Property - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    Includes: Calvin Coolidge Memorial Foundation; Echo Acre; Talbot House; Woodstock Council on Aging.
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Property - Billings Park Commission, 2001-2006 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Property - JY Ranch, 2001-2006 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Property - JY Ranch Visits, 2001-2006 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Property - Woodstock - Marsh Billings Farm and Museum, 2001-2006 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Property - Woodstock - Woodstock Foundation, 2001-2006 (Box 66, Folder 10-11)
    Includes: Elizabeth Billing's Letter; Boards of Directors and Trustees; Fund for Vermont Geography Education; Muller Project; River Walk. Waldorf School.
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Property - Woodstock - Woodstock Foundation - Annual Meeting of the Advisory Board, 2001-2004 (Box 66, Folder 12, Box 67, Folder 1-2)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Property - Woodstock - Woodstock Inn and Resort, 2001-2006 (Box 67, Folder 3-4)
    Includes: Suicide Six.
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Property - Woodstock - Woodstock Resort Corporation, 2001-2006 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Remarks - A-Z, 2001-2003 (Box 67, Folder 5A)
    Includes: Albert H. Gordon's 100th Birthday at MSKCC (June 18, 2001); BVI Belonger Ceremony (September 26, 2003); Elizabeth J. McCormack 80th Birthday Toast at Room 5600, 2002; Healing Energy Conference, Pocantico, May 1-3, 2002; Family Christmas Luncheon, December 15, 2002.
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Remarks - Reception for Bill Moyers (Hudson Valley Series), 2002 April 10 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Remarks - Historic Hudson Valley, 2002 November 12 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Staff (834 Fifth Ave) - A-Z (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Trips - A-Z, 2001-2003 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    Includes: Caneel Bay and Little Dix Bay (December 23, 2001 - January 2, 2002); Jackson Hole, WY (August 14-22, 2003); University Club, 2002.
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Gifts - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. - Correspondence - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 68, Folder 3)
- Science, 2001-2006; 16
  - Science - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    History of Science Society/
  - BLT Research Team, Inc., 2001-2006 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Center for Psychology and Social Change, 2001-2006 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Heffler Research Institute, 2001-2006 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Institute of Noetic Sciences, 2001-2006 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Motion Sciences Organization, 2001-2006 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - New York Hall of Science, 2001-2006 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Society for Scientific Exploration, 2001-2004 (Box 69, Folder 3)
- Welfare, 2001-2006; 17
  - Welfare - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 69, Folder 4-7)
    Includes: American Friends Service Committee; American Red Cross (Washington, DC); American Red Cross in Greater New York; Association for Children for Enforcement of Support; Burden Center for the Aging; Community Entry Services (CES); Community Foundation of Jackson Hole; Community Foundation of the Virgin Islands; Conway and Pratt Projects, Inc.; Enterprise Community Partners, Inc.; Family Care International; Family Center, Inc.; Food First; Greater New York March of Dimes; Habitat for Humanity of Missoula; Health Advocates for Older People, Inc.; Heritage Health and Housing Inc.; Homes for the Homeless; Institute for the Study of Aging; Jackson Rising Sun Community Development Corporation; King's Daughters; Legal Aid Society; Medstar Health Visiting Nurse Association; Meals on Wheels; Partners for Livable Communities; Rebuilding Together; Ronald McDonald House of New York, Inc.; Edwin J. Thompson Senior Center; Visiting Nurse Alliance of Vermont and New Hampshire; Wheels for Humanity; Windsor Connection Resource Center.
  - Partners for Livable Communities, 2001-2006 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Visiting Nurse Alliance, 2001-2006 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Woodstock Visiting Nurses Association, 2001-2006 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Animals - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    Includes: American Veterinary Medical Frontiers, Inc.; Humane Society's Mountain Shelter; Humane Society of New York; Lucy Mackenzie Humane Society, Inc.; Rough Diamond Ranch, Inc.; School of Veterinary Medicine.
  - Blind - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    Includes: Blind Babies Foundation; Deafness Research Foundation; Eye Bank for Sight Restoration; Freedom Guide Dogs for the Blind; Jewish Guild for the Blind; Helen Keller Worldwide; Recording for the Blind, Inc. Foundation; Scojo Vision, LLC.
  - Blind - Lighthouse International, 2001-2006 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Community Centers - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    Includes: Henry Street Settlement; Stanley M. Isaacs Neighborhood Center, Inc.; Lenox Hill Neighborhood House; Pioneer Homestead, Inc.
  - Family Counseling - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Family Counseling - Public Conversations Project, 2001-2006 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Disabled - A-M, 2001-2006 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    Includes: Fountain House; Jackson Hole Therapeutic Riding Association; Learning Center.
  - Disabled - N-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    Includes: National Organization on Disability; Recording for the Blind and Dyslexic.
  - Disabled - Date Able, 2001-2006 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Disabled - International Center for the Disabled, 2001-2006 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Hearing Aids - National Organization for Hearing Research Foundation, 2001-2006 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - United Funds - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    Includes: United Way of the Tarrytowns; United Way of Westchester and Putnam.
  - United Funds - United Way of New York, 2001-2006 (Box 71, Folder 6)
- Women, 2001-2006; 18
  - Women - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    Includes: Business Council for Peace; Equality Now; International Women's Health Coalition; International Women's Media Foundation; Women's Coalition of St. Croix; Women's Prison Project.
  - Association of Women's Business Centers, 2001-2006 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Women's Club of Pocantico HIlls, 2001-2006 (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Women in Need, Inc., 2001-2006 (Box 72, Folder 1)
- Youth, 2001-2006; 19
  - Youth - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 72, Folder 2-3)
    Includes: Boys Club of New York; Boys and Girls Clubs of America; Boy Scouts of America - Greater New York Councils; Boy Scouts of America - Westchester-Putnam Council; Camp Fire Club of America; Covenant House; Family Center; Family YMCA at Tarrytown; Girl Scouts of the USA; Girls Inc.; Harlem YMCA; Kips Bay Boys and Girls Club, Inc.; Madison Square Boys and Girls Club; Overcoming Obstacles; Police Athletic League; Port Chester Carver Center; Quest Junior Drum and Bugle Corps, Inc.; Chi Chi Rodriguez Youth Foundation; Save the Children; Smokey House Center; YMCA-YWCA Camping Services.
  - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) of Greater New York, 2001-2006 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    Includes: Global Campaign; Greenwich YWCA; YWCA Lowell, MA; YWCA of the USA; YWCA Retirement Fund.
  - Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) of New York City, 2001-2006 (Box 72, Folder 6-7)
  - World Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA), 2001-2006 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Camps - A-Z, 2001-2006 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    Includes: 4-H Camp Waubanong, Inc.; Fresh Air Fund; Nebraska Boys Ranch; YMCA Camping Services.